1. Project title
Tentative title: Examine the effectiveness of Q-learning in executing option delta hedges in the presence of transaction costs

2. Names of all group members 
Lejing Xu
Minh Tran
Xiaohe Yu

3. Name and contact information for your mentor 
Gordon Ritter, gordon.ritter@gmail.com

4. A two or three sentence statement of the problem 
Examine the effectiveness of Q-learning (an area of reinforcement learning) in executing several strategies that take into account investors' risk preferences:        
    a. Capturing arbitrage opportunities in trading a single stock when the stock's dynamics present clear arbitrage opportunities. An example is a stock following a mean reverting process such as the Ornstein–Uhlenbeck process. This is a replication of Ritter(2017).
    b. Execute delta hedges for a stock option and find a hedging strategy in the presence of transaction costs

5. A two or three sentence statement of the approach you intend to take 
The training data for the Q-learning agent is entirely simulated. We intend to use controlled simulation which permits arbitrage opportunities and verify the built q-learner can capture this opportunity without prior information. The same approach is taken for delta hedges. 

6. A two or three sentence statement of your criteria of success
Once the training phase for the agent is concluded, we should be able to show that the agent can then make effective trading decisions in the same market regime and simulation environment. 
To be more specific, after 100 million learning iterations, the agent should make good decisions and generate good PnL for the next 100,000 simulated iterations.
Our goal is to successfully train the agent to implement the strategy and replicate the conclusion in Ritter (2017).

7. A list of references you intend to consult. 

Ritter, G. (2017). Machine Learning for Trading.

Sutton, R. S., & Barto, A. G. (1998). Reinforcement learning: An introduction (Vol. 1, No. 1). Cambridge: MIT press.

Kaelbling, L. P., Littman, M. L., & Moore, A. W. (1996). Reinforcement learning: A survey. Journal of artificial intelligence research, 4, 237-285.

Friedman, J., Hastie, T., & Tibshirani, R. (2001). The elements of statistical learning (Vol. 1, pp. 241-249). New York: Springer series in statistics.
